<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>edge computing | Shanshan Xu&#39;s homepage</title>
    <link>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/en/tag/edge-computing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/en/tag/edge-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>edge computing</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>edge computing</title>
      <link>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/en/tag/edge-computing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A lightweight blockchain-based access control scheme for integrated edge computing in the internet of things</title>
      <link>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/en/publication/preprint/2021/arxiv-zhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/en/publication/preprint/2021/arxiv-zhang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;In view of the security issues of the Internet of Things (IoT), considered better combining edge computing and blockchain with the IoT, integrating attribute-based encryption (ABE) and attribute-based access control (ABAC) models with attributes as the entry point, an attribute-based encryption and access control scheme (ABE-ACS) has been proposed. Facing Edge-Iot, which is a heterogeneous network composed of most resource-limited IoT devices and some nodes with higher computing power. For the problems of high resource consumption and difficult deployment of existing blockchain platforms, we design a lightweight blockchain (LBC) with improvement of the proof-of-work consensus. For the access control policies, the threshold tree and LSSS are used for conversion and assignment, stored in the blockchain to protect the privacy of the policy. For device and data, six smart contracts are designed to realize the ABAC and penalty mechanism, with which ABE is outsourced to edge nodes for privacy and integrity. Thus, our scheme realizing Edge-Iot privacy protection, data and device controlled access. The security analysis shows that the proposed scheme is secure and the experimental results show that our LBC has higher throughput and lower resources consumption, the cost of encryption and decryption of our scheme is desirable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;This paper is about data security in Edge-Iot. To accomplish lightweight encryption outsourcing in an edge-device architecture, improved CP-ABE algorithm. Then to achieve the secure access to IoT data, attempt have been made to implement an attribute-based access control model. Try to build a blockchain network on a restricted terminal, built a lightweight blockchain LBC to adapt to IoT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give a specific comparison:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparison of theoretical overhead with other papers on CP-ABE’s outsourced computation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparing the cost of lightweight blockchain LBC with private Fabric and Ethereum;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give the implementation algorithm of access control related contracts;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not Submit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The biggest problem is that the scene is not clear, the research value is not sufficient;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then the security proof is weak, the research content is not specific enough;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The security strength between access control and ciphertext is repeated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Zhang J, Yuan L, Xu S. A lightweight blockchain-based access control scheme for integrated edge computing in the Internet of Things[J]. arXiv preprint arXiv:2111.06544, 2021.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet of things access control model based on blockchain and edge computing</title>
      <link>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/en/publication/journal-article/2022/joca-zhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/en/publication/journal-article/2022/joca-zhang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;The emergence of edge computing has expanded the scope of Internet of Things （IoT） cloud-terminal architecture. With the reduction of transmission and processing delays of massive data on terminal devices， it also brings new security issues. Aiming at the problem of data security and management issues between edge nodes of IoT and massive heterogeneous devices， and considering that blockchain technology is widely used in the security management of data in distributed systems， an IoT access control model Smart Contract for Attribute-Based Access Control （SC-ABAC） was proposed based on blockchain and edge computing. Firstly， an IoT access control architecture integrated with edge computing was proposed， and by combining smart contracts with Attribute-Based Access Control （ABAC）， SC-ABAC was proposed and designed. Then， the optimization of Proof of Work （PoW） consensus algorithm and the access control management flow of SC-ABAC were given. Experimental results show that the time consumed by the proposed model increases linearly with the number of times under continuous access to the block， the Central Processing Unit （CPU） utilization rate is stable， and the CPU security is good during the continuous access process. In this model， the time consumption of calling contracts in the query process only increases linearly with the times， and the time consumptions of the strategy addition and judgment process are both constant. And the optimized consensus mechanism has about 18.37 percentage points less time consumption than PoW consensus per 100 blocks. Therefore， the proposed model can provide decentralized， fine-grained and dynamic access control management in the IoT environment， and can reach consensus faster in a distributed system to ensure data consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./JOCA-Zhang.pdf&#34;&gt;Download paper here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;This paper is about IoT security. In the cloud-edge-end architecture, try to implement access control based on blockchain and give a SC-ABAC model and a simple prototype. SC-ABAC is Smart Contract for Attribute-Based Access Control, and the POW consensus algorithm has been improved in the prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congratulations!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
From July 2023, this paper was selected as a China Knowledge Network Academic Essentials &lt;strong&gt;Highly Cited Paper&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Highly Downloaded Paper&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
