<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>remote sensing | 许姗姗的个人主页</title>
    <link>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/zh/category/remote-sensing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/zh/category/remote-sensing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>remote sensing</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>zh-Hans</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>remote sensing</title>
      <link>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/zh/category/remote-sensing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of surface water temperature and its spatial-temporal variation characteristics of 11 main lakes in Yunnan-Guizhou Plateau</title>
      <link>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/zh/publication/journal-article/2023/jstars-xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/zh/publication/journal-article/2023/jstars-xu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;In the context of global warming, the Lake Surface Water Temperature (LSWT) exhibits a general upward trend. As an indicator of climate change, the surface water temperature of plateau lakes is particularly sensitive to climate warming. In this study, the machine learning model and physical process model are combined to predict water temperature in lake systems: The Air2water model and the Long Short Term Memory (LSTM) model are combined to form a prediction model for the inversion and prediction of 11 typical plateau lakes in the Yunnan-Guizhou Plateau. The modeling results show that the Air2water model performs best, followed by the LSTM model. Overall, the Air2water model and the LSTM model effectively reproduce the monthly, seasonal, and interannual variations of LSWT dynamics in the 11 lakes. The research results show that the LSWT data set from 2021 to 2025 is constructed based on the forecast result, and it is found that six lakes, including Caohai, Dianchi, Erhai, Qionghai, Xingyun Lake and Yangzonghai, showed significant warming in the next five years (the maximum warming rate was less than +0.2 ∘ C/year), while the remaining five lakes showed no significant changes, and the size classification of LSWT data in different spaces on the interannual scale was consistent with the classification of altitudes. By conducting extensive exploration and research on the inversion of LSWT using physical process models and machine learning models, this study offers novel solutions for LSWT prediction and inversion. The study also provides a solid theoretical and practical foundation for future LSWT research, thereby holding practical significance and research value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./JSTARS-Xu.pdf&#34;&gt;Download paper here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nov. 2023: 祝贺！！我们的1篇论文被JSTARS（JCR Q1) 录用！</title>
      <link>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/zh/news/2023/1129/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/zh/news/2023/1129/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[29/11/23]&lt;/strong&gt; 我们的论文 &lt;a href=&#34;https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/zh/publication/journal-article/2023/jstars-xu/&#34;&gt;Prediction of surface water temperature and its spatial-temporal variation characteristics of 11 main lakes in Yunnan-Guizhou Plateau&lt;/a&gt; 已经被 &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/RecentIssue.jsp?punumber=4609443&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(JCR Q1 IF=4.7)&lt;/strong&gt; 录用， 祝贺！！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;awared&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /zh/news/2023/1129/2023-awared-11_hu700275244aab45103b63a9bdebf71928_1573436_aea9eb9ce83e810cf7dd88260dc91117.webp 400w,
               /zh/news/2023/1129/2023-awared-11_hu700275244aab45103b63a9bdebf71928_1573436_62fc971376cb0063418362243f5f9876.webp 760w,
               /zh/news/2023/1129/2023-awared-11_hu700275244aab45103b63a9bdebf71928_1573436_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/zh/news/2023/1129/2023-awared-11_hu700275244aab45103b63a9bdebf71928_1573436_aea9eb9ce83e810cf7dd88260dc91117.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;537&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban Land Surface Temperature Monitoring and Surface Thermal Runoff Pollution Evaluation Using UAV Thermal Remote Sensing Technology</title>
      <link>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/zh/publication/journal-article/2021/suutainability-xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Xu-shan-shan.github.io/zh/publication/journal-article/2021/suutainability-xu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;With the continuous advancement of urbanization, the impervious surface expands. Urbanization has changed the structure of the natural land surface and led to the intensification of the urban heat island (UHI) effect. This will affect the surface runoff temperature, which, in turn, will affect the surface water temperature of urban lakes. This study will use UAS TIR (un-manned aerial system thermal infrared radiance) remote sensing and in situ observation technology to monitor the urban space surface temperature and thermal runoff in Kunming, Yunnan, in summer; explore the feasibility of UAS TIR remote sensing to continuously observe urban surface temperature during day and night; and analyze thermal runoff pollution. The results of the study show that the difference between UAS TIR LSTs and in situ LSTs (in situ air temperature 10 cm above the ground.) varies with the type of land covers. Urban surface thermal runoff has varying degrees of impact on water bodies. Based on the influence of physical factors such as vegetation and buildings and meteorological factors such as solar radiation, the RMSE between UAS LSTs and in situ LSTs varies from 1 to 5 °C. Land cover types such as pervious bricks, asphalt, and cement usually show higher RMSE values. Before and after rainfall, the in situ data of the lake surface water temperature (LSWT) showed a phenomenon of first falling and then rising. The linear regression analysis results show that the R2 of the daytime model is 0.92, which has high consistency; the average R2 at night is 0.38; the averages R2 before and after rainfall are 0.50 and 0.83, respectively; and the average RMSE is 1.94 °C. Observational data shows that thermal runoff quickly reaches thermal equilibrium with the land surface temperature about 30 min after rainfall. The thermal runoff around the lake has a certain warming effect on LSWT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./Sustainability-Xu.pdf&#34;&gt;Download paper here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
